# Viola De Frenza Game Programmer

☑ crowind.gdev@gmail.com | in Linkedin | Genoa, Italy

#### **Profile**

Born in Pisa, 1994



After getting my computer science degree I decided to focus on videogame development. I joined the TheSign Comics and Arts Academy in 2018, from where I graduated in september 2021 with full marks.

During my education I have studied and applied multiple fields, like Artificial Intelligence, Procedural Animations, Procedural Generation, and Tool Programming. My favourites were Shaders and Code Architecture.

I always try to be versatile: I extend tools and libraries when needed and I do extensive researches prior to implementing new algorithms or structures. I also have basic skills in 2D art and game design.

In my 3+ experience in Untold Games I've learnt a lot about optimization and debugging, especially in graphic and rendering problems resolution, both at lower and higher level in Unreal Engine. I have worked extensively on both Nintendo Switch and Nintendo Switch 2, optimizing games on both cpu and gpu sides.

# Work Experience

### **Programmer, Tech Artist**

**Untold Games** 

2022 - Current *Genoa, full-time* 

- Shipped Split Fiction for Nintendo Switch 2 (porting)
- Shipped Tales of Kenzera: Zau for Nintendo Switch (co-dev).
- Shipped Batman: Arkham Trilogy for Nintendo Switch (porting).
- Shipped It Takes Two for Nintendo Switch (porting).
- Studied render pipelines and render debugging on Nintendo Switch, PlayStation 5, and Windows.
- Taught the Materials and Rendering sections of Epic Games' Kickstart program to various teams, both in English and Italian.

Office assistant 2019 - 2021

Lucca Manga School Lucca, part-time

Video Editing, Social Media Management, Mail Management, Database Management.

# Education

Università di Pisa

Pisa, Italy

Bachelor degree in Computer Science, 99/110

Sept 2013 - May 2019

TheSign Comics & Art Academy | Event Horizon

Firenze

Game Programming, 30L/30

Sept 2018 - Sept 2021

# Personal Projects

Roll with the Tiles | Solo Project | C#, UnityJune 2020 - CurrentVampire Nights | Shaders | hlsl, UnityJune 2021 - Sept 2021Lost in the Unknown | Programming, Design | C#, hlsl, UnityNov 2019 - CurrentBeyond Machines | Programming, Design | C#, UnityNov 2018 - July 2019My Travel Agency Lazio | GamesForTourism | Programming, Design | C#, UnityOct 2021Re-Pair | GGJ2020 | Programming | C#, hlsl, UnityJan 2020A Back of Gold | IFGJ2019 | Programming | C#, UnitySept 2019

#### Skills

Human Languages: Italian, English (C1 Grade B)

Languages: C/C++, C#/F#, hlsl, HTML/CSS, Java, LaTeX

Frameworks: Unity, Unreal Engine

Developer Tools: JetBrains Rider, Visual Studio, Adobe Photoshop, Vegas Pro, FMOD Studio, Blender

Version Control: Git, P4V, TortoiseSVN, Plastic

Unity Assets: Rewired, Amplify Shader Editor, Behavior Designer, Odin, DOTween

#### Extracurriculars

# **Fighting Game Community**

2015 - Current

ToSmash - Super Smash Bros. Toscana

- Contributed to the organization of more than 100 Super Smash Bros. for WiiU and Super Smash Bros. Ultimate offline tournaments
- Designed the whole entirety of graphic products (*Power Rankings, Streaming Layouts, Advertising, Logo*)

Rivals of Aether Italia

- Contributed to the organization of more than 50 Rivals of Aether online tournaments
- Designed numerous graphic products (Power Rankings, Advertising)

Super Smash Bros. Italia

• Designed Power Rankings for Winter 2017/2018, Spring 2018 and Fall 2018

#### Misc.

- · Italian and English tournament commentary
- · Community management

# Hobbies

- I'm an avid player of tabletop games, especially strategic games like Brass, Concordia or Scythe.
- I've played guitar and other instruments for years, I also recorded a short album with a video-game soundtracks cover band!
- I enjoy casual hiking since I was a child. Looking for chestnuts, raspberries and blackberries also makes the hiking experience precious to me.
- I'm a huge birds lover, especially crows, ravens and parrots.